where would you see the future of
shawarma how college moving in terms of
new programs the doubting miss state
what would what's your personal hope
that you would like to see here I think
it's very important that we get the
right land-use here that's consistent
with the insights that we've been given
in which we're developing I don't just
mean around the grounds of the college
but I mean over the whole estate because
the land is primary I mean the tribal
indigenous people have taught us that
that the land is where all we or
goodness comes from and at the moment
we're treating our land very very badly
we're farming it intensively and I think
sure I would like to see Schumer has
influence extend out to change the
farming practice towards more
permaculture ish ways of farming or
dealing with the land but I also I think
she apology or Dartington as a whole has
the potential to of becoming a very
important Green University where we're
exploring everything that a conventional
University explores but from a deeper
logical perspective they've got the
buildings here we've got the potential
here what we need of course is a demand
from the general public but we have this
potential to become a very important
perhaps the world's first Green
University so that would mean
departments well though it wouldn't be
separate departments that we'd be
working on green economics green
agriculture health care Deep Ecology
land use practices all of which are
deeply ecological and that's the crisis
becomes more more serious as and as
people understand how serious the crisis
is more more people want to come and
study in a place like this so did you
see and the estate turning into both a
green University but also like an an eco
village or yes I think the two would be
inseparable hmm and University it
wouldn't be the right word either means
visual works on the old
from the old paradigm we aren't really
appropriate because there wouldn't be
clear distinctions between departments
like there is there wouldn't be
department as there are in conventional
universities people with multitasking
doing different sorts of things the
learning would be very experienced there
would be a theoretical component but it
also be embodied through all sorts of
practices out in the world and the
community would be very much involved
too so there's great potential for
developing that here I also think there
should be a and lots of colleges or
places like this around the world and
sure how college could be sort of the
mothership for all those institutions or
all those places that are needed in
every continent to some extent that is
already being developed through an Gaia
education and the global eco village
Network and yes with a very much like
you described curriculum that is
holistic experiential teaching and links
into local communities do you see that
there might be a place to actually
collaborate with yes sure we haven't
explored that very much hmmm and when I
say issue my college is the monk
mothership well it doesn't have to be
yeah at all you know it's not necessary
we could be one under the places where
this happens what we can offer here is
quite a strong theoretical understanding
of holistic science economics or the
whole area in ecological thinking and we
need to expand now to to make ourselves
more practically based but I'm not sure
there are many other places that can
offer that deeper theoretical intuitive
and intellectual understanding of both
the reasons for the cause of crisis and
its solutions which is this through the
extended faculty like all the people
that could come and teach you are you
hoping to develop the and the an actual
resident faculty of people that that
could deliver that kind of well on the
short time no
happened in the long-term it all depends
on how much demand there is so what we
do hmm
so it could expand in that sense but at
the moment we're not thinking of
expanding the faculty hmm very much
we're thinking of starting a new
master's degree in something like
ecological design hmm but other than
that we're going to have a certificate
program in holistic education but other
than that no I mean there's no plans to
make it here hire lots of new faculty